<!--
  ~ Copyright (c) 2013 KloudTek Ltd
  -->

<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">
    <title>Execution Lifecycle</title>
    <para>
        When a resource is created, all tasks assigned to the INIT stage are immediately executed.
    </para>
    <para>
        When the systyrant context is executed, it will go through the following lifecycle stages:
    </para>
    <para>
        <emphasis role="bold">Prepare Stage</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
        At this stage, it will iterate through every resource and call their PREPARE actions until there are no more
        unprocessed resources for this stage.
    </para>
    <para>
        The validation stage exists exclusively to allow the creation / initialization of hosts. The Host
        implementations
        cannot be accessed at that stage (but on the other hand this is the only time where host overrides can be
        assigned
        to resources).
    </para>
    <para>
    After this is done it will:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Validate all resources attributes</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>For every resource which has no 'id' attribute, it will generate one. It will use the
                resource's type name with a number (starting at 1, incrementing it until it generates a valid id).
                So a core.file resource with no id will generate a 'file1' id if there are no sibling resources with
                that id already.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>
                For every resource which has no 'uid' attribute, it will generate one. If the resource has a parent,
                the uid will be generated in the format of '[parent uid].[resource id]'. If it has no parent then
                it will just use the resource id.
            </para></listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>It will re-order the resources based on their dependencies and notifications/subscriptions</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
        <emphasis role="bold">Execute Stage</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
        <emphasis>Note: From this point onwards, resource creations are no longer allowed, nor can the context host or
        resource host overrides be changed.</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
        For each task in the resource it will then:
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Invoke all EXECUTE tasks</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Invoke all VERIFY tasks, and for each verify that returns false, execute the respective SYNC tasks.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the resource has a parent, and this was the last of it's childrens to be executed, it will
                    invoke any POSTCHILDREN tasks the parent has.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para>
        <emphasis role="bold">Cleanup Stage</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>
        At this final stage it will invoke each action's CLEANUP actions.
    </para>
</chapter>
